Raul A. Cruz

raulcruzquintanilla10@gmail.com - (713) 799- 3788

OBJECTIVE

Pursuing an internship opportunity in insurance underwriting, Contributing, over four years of customer service experience in sales, economic theoretical and analytical knowledge, basic descriptive statistical insight, an intermediate level in Microsoft Excel for data manipulation, and willingness to learn and gain valuable experience in the Insurance industry.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Economics Double minor in Finance, and Construction Management University of Houston Current GPA: 3.85/4.0 UH COT Dean's list: Spring and Fall of 2019.

Associate of Arts, General Studies Lone Star College Cv-Fair

Final GPA: 3.59/4.0

Lone Star College Cy-fair president's lists: Spring and Fall of 2016, 2017, 2018.

Research Projects: "Architectural and Construction Development in Ancient Rome and Its influence on Contemporary Times" for Honors Humanities.

SKILLS

- Intermediate Excel data manipulation skills (Excel tables, descriptive statistical functions, Pivot Tables, charts and basic dashboards, lookup functions, logical functions, data validation and manipulation, basic Macros).
- Basic descriptive statistical functions in programming language R.
- Understanding of financial reports (Income Statement, Balance Sheet, Statement of Cash Flow, and Statement of Shareholder's equity).
- Fluent in Spanish.
- Microsoft Office suite SAM training (Word, Excel, PowerPoint).
- Intermediate to advanced knowledge on Oracle's Primavera P6 project management software.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Banana Republic Factory, GAP INC. Katv, TX

August 2019- December 2020

Expected graduation: May 2022

Graduated: December 2018

Brand Ambassador

- Satisfy sales goals by addressing clients' concerns on attires and made suggestions for occasions.
- Report store's sales performance metrics to the management team.
- Communicate the benefits of the store's credit card and assist clients in the application process.
- Solve customer's concerns on returns and guaranteed its proper processing.

Nautica, ABG LLC. **Katy and Cypress, TX Sales Associate**

August 2015 - December 2017 and January 2018 - August 2019

• Interacted with customers daily.

- Achieved the highest sale in 2017, \$1,080.
- Finalized sales at the point of purchase.
- Managed sales and stock of the fragrance department during the holiday season.